Guide to the Matthew Vassar Papers, 1730-1975
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series IV. Property and Financial Papers - Personal and Business
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Executor's account of estate, 1869-1875; (1 volume) (Folder 28.843)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Letters testamentary, (2 items) (Folder 34.844)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Inventory, (1 item) (Folder 34.845)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: 1868 income, income tax form, (2 items) (Folder 34.846)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Real Estate- Auction (folder 1 of 2), (2 items) (Folder 34.847)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Real Estate- Auction (folder 2 of 2), (4 items) (Folder 34.848)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Articles of Agreement (folder 1 of 2), (4 items) (Folder 34.849)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Articles of Agreement (folder 2 of 2), (5 items) (Folder 34.850)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: List of Securities willed to, received by Vassar College, (1 item) (Folder 34.851)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Final decree, (1 item) (Folder 34.852)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: August Rents 1868 (folder 1 of 2), (9 items) (Folder 34.853)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: August Rents 1868 (folder 2 of 2), (8 items) (Folder 34.854)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: November Rents 1868, (9 items) (Folder 34.855)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: February, May Rents 1869, (11 items) (Folder 34.856)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Receipts of Legatees (folder 1 of 4), (14 items) (Folder 34.857)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Receipts of Legatees (folder 2 of 4), (14 items) (Folder 34.858)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Receipts of Legatees (folder 3 of 4), (12 items) (Folder 34.859)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Receipts of Legatees (folder 4 of 4), (12 items) (Folder 34.860)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Receipts from Caroline Vassar (folder 1 of 2), (15 items) (Folder 34.861)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Receipts from Caroline Vassar (folder 2 of 2), (13 items) (Folder 34.862)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Checks (folder 1 of 7), 27 Sep 1868- 24 Oct 1868; (1 envelope) (Folder 34.863)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Checks (folder 2 of 7), 26 Oct 1868 - 26 Jan 1869; (1 envelope) (Folder 34.864)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Checks (folder 3 of 7), 1 Feb1869 - 4 May 1869; (1 envelope) (Folder 35.865)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Checks (folder 4 of 7), 4 May 1869 12 Aug 1869; (1 envelope) (Folder 35.866)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Checks (folder 5 of 7), 12 Aug 1869- 3 Jan 1870; (1 envelope) (Folder 35.867)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Checks (folder 6 of 7), 3 Feb 1870 - Jun 1870; (1 envelope) (Folder 35.868)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Checks (folder 7 of 7), 1872-1876; (1 envelope) (Folder 35.869)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Farmers, Manufacturer's National Bank, Account book, (1 volume) (Folder 28.870)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Checks, Union Trust Co.- checks, (1 envelope) (Folder 35.871)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Checks, Union Trust Co.- Account book, (1 envelope) (Folder 35.872)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Checks, Union Trust Co.- checks, checks balance sheet, (7 items) (Folder 35.873)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Check book, Union Trust Co., 1869-1876; (1 volume) (Folder 28.874)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 1 of 13), 19 Mar 1868 - 27 Jun 1868; (16 items) (Folder 35.875)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 2 of 13), 28 Jun 1868 - 21 Jul 1868; (15 items) (Folder 35.876)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 3 of 13), 23 Jul 1868- 1 Sep 1868; (15 items) (Folder 35.877)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 4 of 13), 1-28 Sep 1868; (15 items) (Folder 35.878)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 5 of 13), 29 Sep 1868- 9 Oct 1868; (15 items) (Folder 35.879)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 6 of 13), 10 Oct 1868 - 2 Nov 1868; (15 items) (Folder 35.880)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 7 of 13), 2 Nov 1868 - 4 Jan 1869; (15 items) (Folder 35.881)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 8 of 13), 4 Jan 1869 - 1 Feb 1869; (15 items) (Folder 36.882)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 9 of 13), 1 Feb 1869 - 30 Mar 1869; (15 items) (Folder 36.883)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 10 of 13), Mar 1869 - 4 May 1869; (15 items) (Folder 36.884)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 11 of 13), 3 May 1869 - 14 Oct 1869; (15 items) (Folder 36.885)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 12 of 13), 1 Nov 1869 - 20 May 1870; (15 items) (Folder 36.886)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Paid Bills (folder 13 of 13), 11 Jun 1870 - 28 Mar 1875; (13 items) (Folder 36.887)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Litigation with Charles Vassar Estate (folder 1 of 3), 1869-1870; (10 items) (Folder 36.888)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Litigation with Charles Vassar Estate (folder 2 of 3), 1870; (3 items) (Folder 36.889)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Litigation with Charles Vassar Estate (folder 3 of 3), 1861-1870; (10 items) (Folder 36.890)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Litigation with James Vassar Estate—Testimony (folder 1 of 6), (2 items) (Folder 36.891)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Litigation with James Vassar Estate—Petition on appeal, appeal (folder 2 of 6), (2 items) (Folder 36.892)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Litigation with James Vassar Estate—Brief on appeal (folder 3 of 6), (9 items) (Folder 36.893)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Litigation with James Vassar Estate (folder 4 of 6), (10 items) (Folder 36.894)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Litigation with James Vassar Estate (folder 5 of 6), (4 items) (Folder 36.895)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Litigation with James Vassar Estate—Last Will and Testament of James Vassar (folder 6 of 6), 21 Nov 1853; (1 item) (Folder 36.906)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Miscellaneous- Indenture, Sales on Sundry Articles, (2 items) (Folder 36.896)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Miscellaneous—Indenture, Sales on Sundry Articles (folder 1 of 4), (14 items) (Folder 36.897)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Miscellaneous—Indenture, Sales on Sundry Articles (folder 2 of 4), (15 items) (Folder 36.898)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Miscellaneous—Indenture, Sales on Sundry Articles (folder 3 of 4), (15 items) (Folder 36.899)
  - Estate of Matthew Vassar: Miscellaneous-Indenture, Sales on Sundry Articles (folder 4 of 4), (17 items) (Folder 36.900)
- Series V. Images
  - Silhouettes (Box 42)
  - Ambrotype (Box 43)
  - Daguerreotypes (Box 44)
- Series VI. Typescripts and Photostats
  - Photostats of originals, 1815-1838 (Box 37)
  - Photostats of originals, 1839-1841 (Box 38)
  - Photostats of originals, 1842-1844 (Box 39)
  - Booth and other typescripts (Box 40)
  - Typescripts (Box 41)